A Guide to the Papers of the President, Office Administrative Files 1904-1915
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the President, Office Administrative Files 1904-1915
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-2/1/2.472 I
This collection consists of ca. 9,600 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access restrictions may apply to specific student records under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.)
Acquisition Information
Archival transfer from the Office of the President, 1947 March 4, 1947 May 7.
Scope and Content Information
These files (ca. 9,600 items) constitute the major record series generated by Edwin Anderson Alderman, the first president of the University of Virginia. The records consist chiefly of correspondence, but also include reports, minutes, clippings, memoranda, and related papers concerning all areas of business of the president's office.
Subject Index
Subjects are listed alphabetically and followed by their folder numbers.
accountancy, state board of, 38
accounting system for University of Virginia, 51, 57
Administrative Committee of the Faculty on Literary Societies report to Alderman, 131
Administrative Committee of the Faculty, 52
Albemarle Normal and Collegiate Institute, 2
Alderman, Edwin A.-- accepts presidency of University of Virginia, 124; honorary degree from Dartmouth, 65; reforms in workload and supervision of students, 38; re: support of the University for the Commons, 49
Aldrich, Norton A., 1
Alleman, L. J., 1
Alumni, 193
Alumni Association--correspondence of D. W. Thom, 192
Alumni of the University in Congress, 52
Alumni Trustees of the Endowment Fund, 198 American Academy in Rome, 35, 141
appropriations for University of Virginia, 184
Association of American Universities, 2
Association of the Colleges and Preparatory Schools of the Southern States, 2
athletics--Calfee controversy, 51; Thorpe case, 35
Ball, T. R.-- Honor System at Johns Hopkins University, 35
Ballard, Marshall--Thorpe case, 35
Bangs, Lois A.--brass plate for the Poe Room, 35
Baptist ministers, 175
Barbour-Page Fund--gift of Mrs. Thomas Nelson Page, 80
Barbour-Page Lectures--first three lecturers, 182
Barney and Lee, Attorneys--donation for study of cancer, 38
Barrow, W. W.--establishment of state board of accountancy, 38
Baskerville, Charles--Thorpe case, 35
Baylor, John Roy--student recruitment, 36
Beardsley, E. P.--honor system at the University of Colorado, 36
bequests--B. W. Green, 192; Edmund W. James, 126; Frances L. Wilson, 212; "Merry Mills", 56; Philip Francis Dupont, 69
Berkeley, William--Thorpe case, 35
Bilisoly, E. A.--Thorpe case, 35
Bird, Robert M.--state commissions on depletion of natural resources, 38
Bishop, Samuel--General Education Board, 35
Bitter, Karl-- sculptor for statue of Thomas Jefferson, 38
Blackwell, R. E.--criticism of high school's preparation of college students, 36; University of Virginia and the University College of Medicine in Richmond, 35
Boatwright, F. W.--re: entry of Richmond College into the Southern Association, 35
Bond issue in Louisiana, 1
Boyle, James E.--questions re: fraternities at the University of Virginia, 36
Brockman, W. W.-- resignation as secretary of Y.M.C.A., 85; Y.M.C.A. "Notes" editorial, 38
Brooke, Richard R.--portrait of Woodrow Wilson, 38
Brown, Elmer Ellsworth, 35, exhibits for Exposition in Quito, Ecuador, 38, "The University of Virginia, A Statement of Accomplishment and Growth", 38
Brown, Glenn--American Academy in Rome, 35
Bruce, Philip Alexander, 35
Bryan, John Stewart-- editorial re: Alderman appointment, 35; Thorpe case, 35
Bryan, St. George T. C.--collection of Indian wares, 35
Bryan, William Jennings--Founder's Day speaker, 38
Burch, Robert L.- -recommendation of Collins Denny for the chair of Moral Philosophy, 35
Burke, Frances M.--Thomas Jefferson's New Testament with texts used in "Compilations of the Sayings of Jesus" removed, 104
Butler, Nicholas--Carnegie Foundation, 35; honorary LL.D. for Edwin Alderman, 35
Butler, Nicholas Murray--bill to incorporate the National Education Association, 37; International Committee on the character-forming influence of schools, 37
Buttrick, Wallace--Alderman's nomination to the General Education Board, 37; General Education Board, 35; Southern Education Board, 35
Byrd, Richard E.--views re: football, 96
Cabell, Walter Coles - re: newspaper publicity for University of Virginia, 51
Calhoun, Patrick-- establishment of the Calhoun fellowships, 50; San Francisco earthquake of 1906, 50
cancer research--donation for study, 38
C & A Railroad, 51
Carnegie, Andrew--endowment, 49; requests report re: disposition of fund established for University of Virginia, 53
Carnegie Foundation, 36, 53; report from University of Virginia re: the organization, faculty, salaries, and budget of the University, 50
Carnegie Fund pension, 103
Carnegie Institute, 51
Cary, Isaac--property in Richmond, 88
Catalogue Committee, 51
Catlett, Charles--geology at University of Virginia, 49; need for a state geological survey, 49
Cemetery, Committee on the Report, 49, 51
Chaloner, John Armstrong--bequest of the "Merry Mills," 56
Chinese literature-- proposed chair, 65
Christian, W. G.-- typhoid problem at University of Virginia, 49
Cicero--gift of a bronze bust from Tiffany & Company, 49
Civic Club, 52
Colonnade Club, 52
Commons, Committee on the-- report, 52
Confederate Memorial Tablets on Rotunda, 64
Congress - members alumni of University of Virginia, 52
Convocation, 52
Cook, John--re: attracting Andrew Carnegie endowment, 49
Coolidge, Mrs. J. Randolph--re: statue of Thomas Jefferson for University of Virginia, 50
Cooperative Education Association of Virginia, 50
Cooperative Education Commission, 83
Council on Medical Education of the American Medical Association--meeting, 49
Craighead, E. B.--General Education Board, 50; Peabody Fund, 50
Crawley, Edwin S.--re: admission requirements, 50
Crenshaw, Lewis D.--re: "School of Athens" painting, 50
Curry, Jabez Lamar Monroe--biography, 130; statue by Sodini, 50
Curry Memorial School. 110
Dabney, R. H.--need to encourage return of students, 63
Dancy, Frank Battle--biographical sketch, 64
Daniel, John W., 63
Davis, G. O.--re: Virginia Christian College, 64
Davis, Mrs. N. K.--re: Confederate Memorial Tablets, 64
Davis, William Holmes--re: school facilities, 63
Dawson, N. E.-- simplified spelling, 64
Day, Nancy--student exchange program between University of Virginia and Harvard, 64 Debating and Oratorical Council, 131
Denny, Collin-- recommended for chair of Moral Philosophy, 35 dining halls, 49, 52
Diplomatic and Consular Service, 52
"Dixie"--original manuscript owned by Emmett, 71
Dodge, Cleveland H.--history of the Y.M.C.A., 63; Madison Hall opening, 63 donations, 102
Drake, James H.--chair of Chinese literature, 65
Drinking at University of Virginia, 2, 131
Dupont, Philip Francis--bequest, 69
earthquake--San Francisco (1906), 209
Economics chair, 64
education--Peabody chairs, 83
Emmett, Daniel Decatur--owner of original manuscript of "Dixie", 71
endowment fund, 53
engineering--programs of various Virginia schools compared, 75
entrance requirements for Virginia colleges, 36
Episcopal ministers, 175
Episcopal Theological Seminary, 175
ethnology and archaeology o the South, 71
Exposition in Quito, Ecuador--exhibits, 38
Ezekial, Moses-- bronze statues for University of Virginia, 162; installation of the Homeric Group in bronze, 80
Faulkner, W. H.--status, 77
Fenner, Judge Charles E.--re: establishment of Peabody chairs of education in Southern Universities, 83
Ficklen, H. C.--re: exclusion of Balzac and Maupassant from a library, 84
Fife, Robert--re: Thorpe case, 83
Fitzhugh, Thomas - illness, 83
Flannagan, Roy K.--re: need for medical and dental care for rural children, 79
football--modification of the game, 96; physical danger of the sport, 96
forest lands of University of Virginia, 97
forestry instruction at University of Virginia, 164
forestry program--establishment at University of Virginia, 164
Founder's Day-- cancellation of the 1910 exercises, 99
Founder's Day speaker--William Jennings Bryan, 38
fraternities--regulation and attitude of administration, 36
Gaines, William H.--re: students from the Phillippines, 100
Gambling at the University of Virginia, 2
"Gateway" of University of Virginia--inscription on, 102
General Education Board, 37, 50, 100, 164
geological survey for Virginia, 49, 58
Glass, Carter-- retirement from the Board of Visitors, 101
Glass, Edward Christian, 100
Gordon, Armistead C.--reappointment to the Board of Visitors, 102; service on the Board of Visitors, 101
Gorgas, W. C.-- request for sanitary inspectors on the Panama Canal Zone, 102
Green, B. W. - estate left to University of Virginia, 102
Hamilton, Edith, 111
Harvard student exchange program with University of Virginia, 64 Harvey S. Chase & Co.--re: new accounting system for University of Virginia, 51
Hatcher, Orie L.--re: educational problems in Virginia, 111
Heck, W. H.-- establishment of chair secondary education, 110
Hemphill, J. C.--re: Convocation, 52
History and Political Economy Chair-- financial investment for funding, 35
Homer statue-- installation of bronze statue on the lawn, 80
Hot Feet Society, 4
Indian wares, 35
Isaac Cary scholarship, 88
James, Edward- -re: his will, 51
Jamestown Tercential Exposition--exhibit of University of Virginia, 125
Jarman, J. L., 125, 213
Jefferson, Thomas--"Compilations of the Sayings of Jesus," 104; fund-raising efforts to install the statue of Jefferson on the lawn, 81; installation of the Jefferson statue, 82; letter to Judge Theoderick Bland, 104; re: his letters to Joseph C. Cabell, 51; statue of, 38, 50, 80
Jesse, R. H., 125
Johns Hopkins University--establishment of an honor system, 35
Jusserand, Jean Jules, 124
Kahn Foundation for the Foreign Travel of American Teachers, 129
Kean, Jefferson Randolph - President of Monticello Graveyard Association, 144
Kent, Henry T.--Monroe statue, 128
Khan, Mirza Ali-Kuli Persian students in United States colleges, 129
Lafayette, Marquis de--reproduction of bust modeled by Houdon, 124
Latin requirement for a degree controversy, 67
Lee Memorial-- movement to establish it at University of Virginia, 135
Levy, Jefferson, 2; re: visit by American Historical Association to Monticello, 131
Literary societies--petition to Board of Visitors for funding, 131; report by faculty, 131
Louisiana bond issue, 1
Louthou, Henry T.--re: his life of J. L. M. Curry, 130
McGuire, Mary Madison - re: gift of a Thoms Jefferson letter to Judge Bland, 104
McKim, Charles-- American Academy in Rome, 2; founding of the American Academy in Rome, 141
Madison Hall, 63
Magruder, E. M.--suggestions to improve the University hospital, 140
"Majority Report on Readers" (1906)-- C. L. Patton, 162
Martin, Thomas S.--re: difficulty in securing annual appropriations for University of Virginia, 140
matriculation at University of Virginia, 184
medical and dental needs of rural children, 79
"Merry Mills" bequest, 56
ministerial students, 175
"Minority Report on Readers" (1906)--C. L. Patton, 162
missionaries, 175
Monroe, James - re: gift of his statue to University of Virginia, 83; statue, 128
Monticello--visit by American Historical association, 131
Monticello Graveyard Association, 144
Moral Philosophy--Chair, 35
Mosby, John Singleton, 144; views re: football, 96
Murphy, Edgar Gardner, 144
Museum of Southern Ethnology and Archaeology --suggestions for its establishment, 71
National Board of Trade, 52
National Conservation Commission, 158
National Education Association, 37
"Outline of Alumni Work," 1 Page, Thomas Nelson, 80, 162
Page, Walter Hines, 162; suggestions for new method of teaching English, 77
Panama Canal Zone, 102
Payne, Bruce R.-report re: drinking at University of Virginia, 2; report re: gambling at University of Virginia, 2
Peabody, George Foster, 163
Peabody Board-- discussion of its usefulness, 100
Peabody Fellowship at Tulane University, 1
Peabody Fund, 50, 162, 164
Pendleton, Hunter--establishment of a geological survey for Virginia at University of Virginia, 58
Persian students--study in United States colleges, 129
Phelps-Stokes Fund Fellowship for the Study of the Negro, 205
Pinchot, Gifford--instruction in forestry at University of Virginia, 164
Poe, Edgar A.- brass- plate for the Poe Room on the lawn, 35
Poe School of American Literature, 112
Pollock, Bernice Cally-- right of women to attend University of Virginia, 164
Potts, Allen--re: Calfee athletics controversy, 51
Presbyterian ministers, 175
Price, R. M.--correspondence with the Aldermans, 164
Pritchett, Henry S. - correspondence re: Carnegie Foundation, 53
Professionalism in college athletics, 35
Prussian teacher exchange program, 54
publicity for the University of Virginia, 51
race studies, 205
racial segregation--article by E. G. Murphy, 144
readers, 162
religion- -"Alumni Distinguished in Religious Service," 175; "Students of UVA who Entered the Baptist Ministry", 175; "Students of UVA who Entered the Presbyterian Ministry," 175; "Students of UVA who Served as Foreign Missionaries," 175; "UVA Alumni who Attended Episcopal Theological Seminary of Virginia," 175
"Report of the Committee on the Cemetery of the University," 49, 51
report on the University forest lands, 97
requirements for a degree at University of Virginia, 173
Resolution passed by the National Board of Trade, 52
Richmond alumni of University of Virginia--concern re: attitude of University of Virginia towards athletics, 102
Rockefeller, John D.--donation for the Curry Memorial School, 110
Rotunda--Confederate Memorial Tablets, 64
San Francisco earthquake of 1906, 50, 209
"School of Athens" painting, 50
Senff, Charles H.--memorial of, 102
"Shall the Races be Separated?" 144
Shepardson, Frances W. re: endowed lectureships and publications, 51
Smith, C. Alphonso - appointment, 77
Smith, R. L.--Albemarle Normal and Collegiate Institute, 2
Southern Education Board, 204
Spenser, Samuel--biographical sketch, 183
Standing Committees--memorandum concerning, 52
State Female Normal School, 213
state forester, search for a, 97
Statement of Growth of University of Virginia, 198
Stearnes, R. C.--proposed woman's college, 213; re: University of Virginia enforcement of entrance requirements, 54
Strode, Senator Aubrey T.--re: state appropriations, 184; re: University matriculation, 184
student exchange program, 64
student life-- criticism, 131
students--reforms in work load and supervision, 38; Regulations re: honorable discharge from the University of Virginia, 4
Swanson, Claude A.--commission of Alderman as delegate to the Uniform State Legislation Conference, 198
Thom, Decourcy W., 192
Thomas Jefferson Memorial Endowment Fund report, 53
Thornton, William M.--Chairman of the Committee on Entrance Requirements, 2
Thorpe case, 35, 83
Tidewater Alumni Association of University of Virginia, 193
University of Colorado--establishment of an honor system, 36
University of Virginia-- admission to the Carnegie Foundation, 53 U
niversity of Virginia Hospital, 140
Virginia Christian College, 64
Virginia Polytechnic Institute state annuities, 50
Virginia Summer School of Art, 50
Wheeler, Berry I, earthquake at San Francisco, 209
William and Mary--designation as a normal school, 75
Wilson, Frances L., 212
Wilson, Woodrow--portrait, 38, 104
women at University of Virginia--right to attend, 164
Young Men's Christian Association (Y.M.C.A.), 63; Brockman's resignation as secretary, 85; "Notes" editorial, 38
Contents List
- Office Administrative Files 1904-1915
  - AMiscellaneous 1904-1914, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Academic Schools--Miscellaneous 1908-1914 (Box 1)
  - Administrative Council 1909-1912 (Box 1)
  - Admissions and Permits to Register--"A-Z" 1905, 5 folders (Box 1)
  - Admissions, including Permits to Register 1906 (Box 1)
  - Admissions-- A-Z 1912-1914, 5 folders (Box 2)
  - Alumni Association 1906-1914 (Box 2)
  - Alumni Board--Budgets 1905-1911 (Box 2)
  - Alumni Board--Carnegie Endowment Fund 1908-1914 (Box 2)
  - Alumni Board--Donations and Reports 1906-1910 (Box 2)
  - Alumni Board--Endowment Fund 1905-1913, 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Alumni Board--Investments 1909-1913, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Alumni Board--Meetings 1908-1914 (Box 3)
  - Alumni Board--Treasurer 1905-1914, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Annual Reports 1906-1914 (Box 4)
  - Applications for Positions 1907-1912, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Archer Christian Memorial 1910-1912 (Box 4)
  - Astronomy (1 of 2) 1908-1914 (Box 4)
  - Athletic Committee 1906-1914 (Box 4)
  - BMiscellaneous 1904-1905 (Box 4)
  - Ba-Bo Miscellaneous 1906 (Box 5)
  - Br-By Miscellaneous 1906-1907 (Box 5)
  - BMiscellaneous 1907-1914 (Box 5)
  - Barbour-Page Lecture Fund 1907-1914 (Box 5)
  - Biblical History and Literature 1906-1914 (Box 5)
  - Biology 1908-1914 (Box 5)
  - Boarding Houses 1909-1910 (Box 6)
  - Budgets 1904-1911 (Box 6)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Fraternity House 1907-1910 (Box 6)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Landscape Work 1907-1910 (Box 6)
  - Buildings and Grounds--President's House 1907-1910 (Box 6)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Superintendent's Office 1906-1913 (Box 6)
  - Bursar--Carruthers 1912 (Box 6)
  - CMiscellaneous 1904-1906, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Ca-Ch Miscellaneous 1907-1911 (Box 7)
  - Ci-Cz Miscellaneous 1907-1912 (Box 7)
  - Carnegie Foundation 1907-1914, 3 folders (Box 7)
  - Chaloner, John Armstrong--Bequest of The Merry Mills 1907-1910 (Box 7)
  - Chase, Harvey S. 1907-1911 (Box 7)
  - Chemistry 1906-1914, 3 folders (Box 8)
  - Chinese Students 1907-1909 (Box 8)
  - Convocation 1911-1914 (Box 8)
  - Convocation 1911-1914 (Box 8)
  - DMiscellaneous 1904-1912, 3 folders (Box 8)
  - Dawson's Row 1911 (Box 8)
  - Degrees 1907-1909 (Box 9)
  - Dining Hall 1906-1909 (Box 9)
  - Dupont, P. F.--Bequest 1908 (Box 9)
  - EMiscellaneous 1904-1914, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Economics 1908-1914 (Box 9)
  - Education 1909-1914 (Box 9)
  - Educational Commission 1907-1913, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Engineering 1907-1914 (Box 9)
  - English 1905-1914 (Box 9)
  - Entrance Requirements 1907-1909 (Box 9)
  - Extension Work 1913-1914 (Box 10)
  - Ezekiel Bronzes 1905-1911, 3 folders (Box 10)
  - FMiscellaneous 1904-1914, 3 folders (Box 10)
  - Faculty Legislation n.d. (Box 10)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships 1906-1914, 3 folders (Box 10)
  - Finals 1911-1914 (Box 11)
  - Finance--Budget Statements 1907-1914, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Finance--Fees of Students, deferred 1909 (Box 11)
  - Finance--Fees of Students, return of 1908-1911 (Box 11)
  - Finance--Loan-Funds 1909-1914 (Box 11)
  - Football 1909-1914 (Box 11)
  - Forestry 1908-1914 (Box 11)
  - Forms 1911-1914 (Box 11)
  - Founder's Day 1909-1914 (Box 11)
  - GMiscellaneous 1904-1914, 3 folders (Box 12)
  - Garnett, James M. 1908-1909 (Box 12)
  - Geological Survey 1908-1909 (Box 12)
  - Geology 1907-1913 (Box 12)
  - Germanic Languages 1908-1914 (Box 12)
  - Gifts 1912-1915 (Box 12)
  - Greek 1908-1912 (Box 12)
  - Green, James B. 1907-1909 (Box 12)
  - HMiscellaneous (1-2 of 3) 1904-1913 (Box 12)
  - HMiscellaneous (3 of 3) 1904-1914 (Box 13)
  - History 1906-1914 (Box 13)
  - Hopkins, W. E.--Bequest 1910 (Box 13)
  - IMiscellaneous 1905-1910 (Box 13)
  - Inaugural Invitations--Responses: A-1905, 1-6 of 7 folders (Box 13)
  - Inaugural Invitations--Responses: A-Z1905, 7 of 7 folders (Box 14)
  - Instructors 1907-1914 (Box 14)
  - JMiscellaneous 1904-1912, 2 folders (Box 14)
  - James Bequest 1907-1909 (Box 14)
  - Japanese Exchange Professor 1911-1914 (Box 14)
  - KMiscellaneous 1904-1914, 2 folders (Box 14)
  - LMiscellaneous 1904-1913, 2 folders (Box 14)
  - Latin 1907-1914 (Box 15)
  - Law 1907-1912 (Box 15)
  - Law Building 1908-1912 (Box 15)
  - Robert E. Lee Memorial 1907 (Box 15)
  - Legislative Program 1905-1914, 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Library 1907-1910 (Box 15)
  - Library of Southern Literature 1907-1914 (Box 15)
  - Ma Miscellaneous 1904-1914 (Box 15)
  - Mc Miscellaneous 1904-1914 (Box 15)
  - Manuscripts 1907-1914 (Box 16)
  - Me-Mi Miscellaneous 1904-1914 (Box 16)
  - Mo-Mz Miscellaneous 1904-1914 (Box 16)
  - Mathematics 1908-1914 (Box 16)
  - Medical College 1909-1914 (Box 16)
  - Medical Inspection 1911 (Box 16)
  - Medicine--Anatomy 1909-1914 (Box 16)
  - Medicine--Clinical 1913 (Box 16)
  - Medicine--Eye, Ear, Throat and Nose 1907-1908 (Box 16)
  - Medicine - Hospital 1907-1910 (Box 16)
  - Medicine--Miscellaneous 1904-1914 (Box 16)
  - Medicine--Pathology and Bacteriology 1908-1913 (Box 16)
  - Medicine--Pharmacology and Materia Medica 1907-1911 (Box 16)
  - Medicine--Physiology 1906-1910 (Box 16)
  - Medicine--Public Health and Hygiene 1908-1913 (Box 16)
  - Medicine--Surgery and Gynecology 1910 (Box 16)
  - Na-Ny Miscellaneous 1904-1914 (Box 17)
  - Naval Academy 1912-1913 (Box 17)
  - Noreck, H. 1907-1909 (Box 17)
  - OMiscellaneous 1904 (Box 17)
  - Pa Miscellaneous 1905-1914 (Box 17)
  - Pe-Ph Miscellaneous 1905-1914 (Box 17)
  - Pi-Pz Miscellaneous 1905-1914 (Box 17)
  - Peabody Fund 1909-1912 (Box 18)
  - Philosophy 1909-1914 (Box 18)
  - Physics 1907-1914, 4 folders (Box 18)
  - Positions for Graduates 1907-1909 (Box 18)
  - Public Occasions 1906-1909 (Box 18)
  - Q-Ri Miscellaneous 1904-1914 (Box 18)
  - Ro-Rz Miscellaneous 1904-1914 (Box 18)
  - Religion 1908-1912 (Box 19)
  - Rhodes Scholarship 1904-1914 (Box 19)
  - Rockefeller Commission 1909-1913 (Box 19)
  - Romance Languages 1909-1914 (Box 19)
  - Sa-Se Miscellaneous 1905-1912 (Box 19)
  - Sh-Sm Miscellaneous 1904-1912 (Box 19)
  - Sn-Ss Miscellaneous 1904-1911 (Box 20)
  - St-Sz Miscellaneous 1904-1914 (Box 20)
  - Secondary Education 1906-1914 (Box 20)
  - Society for Preservation of Antiquities 1907-1908 (Box 20)
  - Statistics 1907-1911 (Box 20)
  - Stokes Lectureship 1911-1914 (Box 20)
  - Student Intemperance 1906-1910 (Box 20)
  - Summer School 1907-1914 (Box 20)
  - Summer Work 1911-1914 (Box 20)
  - Ta-Th Miscellaneous 1904-1911 (Box 20)
  - Ti-Tz Miscellaneous 1904-1914 (Box 20)
  - Term Reports 1909-1914, 3 folders (Box 21)
  - Tunstall Memorial Library 1907 (Box 21)
  - UMiscellaneous 1906-1913 (Box 21)
  - University Extension 1911-1913 (Box 21)
  - University Lake 1911 (Box 21)
  - VMiscellaneous 1904-1912 (Box 21)
  - Virginia Students 1912 (Box 21)
  - Visitors--Docket 1911-1914 (Box 21)
  - Visitors--Meetings 1908-1914, 3 folders (Box 21)
  - Visitors--Membership 1907-1912 (Box 21)
  - Wa Miscellaneous 1904-1911 (Box 22)
  - We-Wh Miscellaneous 1904-1913 (Box 22)
  - Wi Miscellaneous 1904-1912 (Box 22)
  - Wo-Wz Miscellaneous 1904-1914 (Box 22)
  - Wilson Bequest 1907 (Box 22)
  - Women's College 1910-1914, 2 folders (Box 22)
  - X-Z Miscellaneous 1905-1910 (Box 22)